♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
It’s fine up to now.
I’ll test this part here again.
Come on!
What do you mean, “eh!”
I don’t believe this! Why does it
always happen just then!
Aelita, did you deactivate the external
sinusoidal modules like I told you to?
Of course. And I even
defragmented the internal matrix.
Huh? But…
I already did that!
The system is bound to screw up
if it gets the same data twice!
if we keep working against each other,
we’re never gonna succeed! Never!
I’m sorry.
Uh, no…
I’m the one who’s sorry, Aelita.
Forgive me.
I shouldn’t have gotten so angry.
It’s okay.
But I think we should stop for tonight.
I’ll see you tomorrow.
No, wait, Aelita!
Goodnight.
Hi, guys.
Well, it looks like I’m not the only one
who’d rather have slept late.
What were you guys doing? Studying, huh?
Not exactly. Tetrix Annihilator.
Till three in the morning.
I should’ve guessed it was
something like that. Nice going!
Thanks. How’d you know I won?
How are you, Jeremie?
Me? I didn’t sleep even a wink.
I’ve got an awful lot on my mind.
Oh, yeah? The usual worries
about materializing Aelita?
No, no. Well, yes, actually.
But there’s a lot more to it than that.
(RINGING)
I’m off.
Nothing like a little math class
to wake me up!
I’ll begin again
since it’s a bit complicated.
Hey, Jeremie!
What is it?
What’s going on with Aelita?
Well, last night we had a bit of a fight.
Yeah, about what?
Nothing.
It was on account of me.
I yelled at her, and I think she got mad.
Ulrich, I really have to go.
Where to? The boy’s room?
Of course not! To Lyoko.
Huh--what!
Ulrich, repeat what I just said!
Uh…
Odd, go on. Help him.
(SNORING)
(LAUGHTER)
What? No way!
Not for very long! Just for an hour!
I could go at lunch time!
But that’s not the problem, Jeremie.
The problem is the super calculator.
You’re the only one who can use it!
Yeah, but once you get the idea,
it’s not complicated.
I can launch a
simplified transfer program,
and explain the procedures to you.
It doesn’t feel right. I’m sorry, Jeremie.
Yumi, listen.
I had an argument with Aelita,
and I want to ask her
to forgive me in person.
What if XANA attacks while you’re there?
Then we just have to
bring him back immediately
and take his place on Lyoko.
Anyway, XANA’s been pretty quiet lately.
Now, I’ve already calculated
the variable virtual mass,
so you don’t have to worry.
Since I won’t be fighting,
I used the default option
for the exponential memory transfer, okay?
As for the fractal encoding
for the blocks, piece of cake!
Piece of cake?
Hey, this may be easy for you,
but it sure isn’t for us!
You do this every time?
Well, yeah.
What do you think?
That I take a nap while you’re on Lyoko?
Anyway, we’ll stay in contact.
And if you have any trouble,
just check my notes.
Your scanner is waiting, sir!
Okay. Be brave, Jeremie.
Have a good trip.
I’m starting the transfer now.
Go.
I just scanned the data chain.
Yumi made a data capture error
that blocked the system.
Which means that the
memory used for transfers
was deactivated at the worst time.
But…where is he?
He wasn’t transferred to Lyoko,
and he didn’t come back to you,
and so he’s…he’s out there and…
locked somewhere between us.
Don’t worry. He’s okay.
Aelita, you have to retrieve memory.
Are you in contact with him?
Yes.
Well, let’s say I think what he thinks.
It’s as if he were part of my mind.
And can we get him back?
Yes.
Jeremie says we have to recover
memory in the four passage towers,
and redirect it to the three scanners
to complete the transfer.
But it’s going to take time.
That’s a hopeful sign. How much time?
Well, the time to go to
each one of the regions
and do all the necessary manipulations
and reinitialize the system,
according to Jeremie,
one of your afternoons.
That means there’s no time to lose.
Okay, I'm off.
Thank you, Aelita.
Look, Yumi, it wasn’t your fault.
Jeremie’s the only one
who can run the computer
without it breaking down.
Yes, I know.
The big problem is that
as long as Jeremie’s in limbo
we can’t go to Lyoko,
and if XANA attacks…
Don’t sweat it, Yumi!
Aelita’s gonna get Jeremie home soon.
I’m positive!
XANA won’t have time to do anything.
You’d better go back to school.
If we’re all absent,
they’ll get suspicious.
I’ll stay here just in case.
Herb?
Present.
Valerie?
Here.
Jeremie?
Jeremie isn’t here?
Uh…he’s, uh, in the infirmary, mam,
trying to get unblocked!
Not surprising. You children
eat much too fast. Now for chemistry.
Hey, what kind of no good
are you creeps up to now?
None of your business.
Well, with that kind of answer,
now I’m sure you’re up to no good.
Can’t fool you, Sissi!
Well, actually, Jeremie’s working on
a new project for making worms intelligent!
That’s right!
And he’d like to test it on you!
(LAUGHING)
Alright, alright! Quiet down!
Yumi, I’m coming to the second tower.
Great, Aelita. Memory recovered.
Two down, two to go.
How you doing, Yumi? Let me see.
How’s it going?
Aelita just left the second tower.
Two to go.
Things are going almost too well.
I’m heading for the forest.
Hey, Yumi, you ought
to relax a little bit.
Aelita will be finished soon.
Why don’t you go back to school?
It’ll take your mind off it.
Yeah, we’ll take over for you!
We’re not missing class.
We’re supposed to be in the library.
Okay.
I’ll see you guys later.
Aelita, I’m replacing Yumi.
Do you read me?
Yes, loud and clear, Ulrich.
I’m almost at the third tower.
Is Jeremie okay?
A little worried, but yeah, he’s okay.
Uh-oh! Trouble!
Ah!
Odd, we got a problem here.
Aelita, I get the feeling
you’re not alone out there.
You’re right, Ulrich. I’m not.
Watch out, Aelita! Better run!
Three more monsters coming! Hurry up!
Ah!
Careful! In front of you!
Aelita, on your left. There’s a platform!
Well done. Jeremie would be proud of you.
I’ll get you connected.
That’s three down.
What do we do now?
Should we tell Yumi?
No, let’s poor Yumi alone.
We haven’t needed her up till now.
By the 1950s, radio and television
had become the most important
means of spreading culture.
In addition, the cinema had its role to play
and did so very dynamically.
In the 1990s, computers
entered people’s homes.
And by the end of the 20th century,
there was a new means
of planetary communication
with the invention of the internet.
I’m in the mountain region.
Just one more tower to go.
Why is she stopping?
Ulrich, I’m at the tower,
but it’s being guarded by two Bloks.
XANA’s gotten the message.
There’s not way you can get through?
No, none. And if I can’t transfer
the memory form the tower,
we’ll lose Jeremie for good.
There’s got to be a way, Aelita.
Wait.
Jeremie says that there may be
a way of retrieving memory elsewhere.
But where?
In another tower?
Another computer?
Another tower’s impossible.
And Jeremie’s convinced that
an external computer’s power
wouldn’t be enough
to operate the three scanners.
What about one?
Just one scanner? I’ll check with him.
But why only one?
To bring Jeremie back,
all three scanners are needed.
Think it over, Odd.
If one of us can succeed
in being transferred to Lyoko,
Aelita will be able to get into the tower.
Ulrich, Odd. I’ve got a problem.
It’s becoming harder and harder
to contact Jeremie.
I’m afraid he’s starting
to delete himself.
Huh? What do you mean, Aelita?
He’s disappearing.
The computer is confusing him
with an outdated file.
You’ve got to bring him back
as soon as possible!
Okay, we have no choice.
Now, who would like to answer?
Ulrich, how are things going?
Huh? Trapped by some Bloks?
Jeremie’s computer?
Okay, I’ll go and get it.
Sir, can I please go to the infirmary?
Hmm…
There it is.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, um, it’s always good
to exercise your mind
after phys ed class, huh, Jim?
(WHISTLES)
I wish Yumi would hurry up.
Ah.
What’s taking you so--
Yeah, well, I got
caught red-handed by Jim.
What!
Uh, no, look, I’m sorry.
I can’t talk right now.
Yumi got caught.
She’s in the principal’s office.
And she’s got the computer with her.
We’re done for now!
There’s absolutely nothing we can do.
Unless…
Listen, Sissi.
I really need your help this time.
Well, well. What do you know?
I’m serious, Sissi. Come on.
Oh!
That’s what you got to do.
It’s really important, Sissi.
What!? You’re completely out of your mind!
The only way I would
do something like that
is if you promise to be
a little more cool with me!
And when I say little,
that means…you know.
Okay, look. I’ll, uh…
I’ll go out with you for a…for a week!
How’s that?
What! A week!
To help Yumi, the price
is two months minimum!
One month and a down payment.
What kind of…down payment, hm?
(ROMANTIC MUSIC)
I don’t understand your story, Miss Ishiyama.
Jeremie couldn’t possibly
have asked you to get his computer
because he happens not
to be in school today. It’s noted here.
But he in on the school grounds, sir.
He’s in the infirmary.
In fact, Yumi herself was reported
absent for part of the day.
And as for Ulrich and Odd--
Enough of that. You and your friends
have accumulated a number of reasons
For being suspended in just a half day.
What do you have to say in your defense!
Daddy!
I’ve got to speak to you, it’s important!
Sissi, can’t you see I’m busy.
I know, daddy, but it’s about Yumi!
Behave yourself! I won’t warn you again!
You’re gonna have to
explain to me how you did that.
I don’t want to talk about it
Yumi, um, you mind if we don’t
see each other for about a…
a month?
Watch out, Aelita!
Aah!
One down! The others are coming.
Hang in there, Aelita.
Listen, Yumi,
what I did was…I mean--
Ulrich, it’s your problem.
But it’s not what you think, I swear!
If that’s all you can think of to say,
don’t say anything.
For the time being, I’ve got a
computer to connect, so save it, huh?
Well, Odd, how’s Aelita doing?
Pretty good up till now.
Fortunately, she runs a lot faster than you.
The big problem, though,
is that she’s losing contact with Jeremie.
I’ll head for the scanners.
Ulrich?
I can’t believe that you kissed Sissi!
If you tell Yumi, you’re dead.
Okay, all we can do now is hope.
Aelita, Ulrich’s gonna try and reach you.
The computer’s connected.
What do I do now?
You’ve got to configure
the auxiliary port to transfer the memory.
Here’s how you do it.
Okay, Aelita. I did it.
I’ve just entered all the data.
Good, Yumi.
You can transfer Ulrich now.
Transfer Ulrich.
Well, go on. Hurry up!
Ulrich?
Do it, Yumi.
I have faith in you.
Go.
Not enough memory!
We came so close,
but it’s just not enough!
We need another 10 bytes!
Uh…
Aelita, watch out behind you.
Transfer Ulrich.
Hurry up!
Sanner Ulrich.
Virtualization!
Impact!
Ulrich!
Sorry I’m late, Aelita.
Hey, Odd, how’d you do it?
A lot of the credit should
go to Tetrix Annihilator, huh?
Hope you weren’t planning on playing it!
Don’t worry, I got enough to do here
without playing other games.
Okay, it’s up to you now.
Bring back Jeremie.
We did it! We’ve retrieved
the scanners’ memories!
Jeremie?
Jeremie, can you hear me?
Wake up.
Jeremie…
Aelita!
-Jeremie!
How are you feeling?
It was…it was…
Fantastic!
(LAUGHTER)
Your crazy idea of going
to Lyoko gave us a real scare.
Look, I’m sorry, but I gotta go.
I promised Sissi.
What are you, her slave?
With that down payment you gave her,
she should leave you alone tonight!
Down payment?
What’s all this about, Ulrich?
Nothing!
See ya later!
Wait, I want an explanation! Ulrich!
Yeah, catch you sometime!
I was afraid you were mad at me.
I thought you were mad, Aelita!
But I understood how you
felt about me when you came…
when you came to get me.
Jeremie, when you’re really in love,
does it mean you fight all the time?
No, not all the time. But it can happen
Really?
You ought to tell that to Ulrich and Yumi!
I’d rather stay out of that one!
Let me talk!
There’s nothing to talk about!
I’m fed up with your lying!
But I’m not lying!
There’s nothing between Sissi and me!
Sure. Goodnight.
Hey, wait! Yumi, let me explain!
Yumi, are you still there?
Yumi!
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO